(法国 里维埃拉 1995年)
嘿
Hey.
哥们 这里不能停车
Yo, boy, you can't park there.
- 我们在做生意 - 我们也是
- We're doing business here. - So are we.
快走
Move it!
你 过来
You, come.
告诉你认识的人 从现在起
Tell everyone you know from now on
法国里维埃拉的性产业归我管
the prostitution on French Riviera belongs to me.
你是谁？
Who are you?
卡拉索夫
Karasov.
去吧
Go now.
安娜 微笑
Anna, smile.
微笑
Smile!
好姑娘
Good girl.
- 你想为我工作吗？- 是的
- You wanna work for me? - Sure.
很好 亲爱的
Good, sweetie.
快点 姑娘们 去工作吧
Come on, girls. Get to work.
试着享受它吧 安娜
Try to enjoy it, Anna.
(十五年后)
- 安娜？- 是我
- Anna? - Yes.
是我 都搞定了 我们都准备好了今晚的行动
It's me. It's done. We're all ready for tonight.
- 一切都安排好了 - 很好
- Everything's set up. - Good.
- 安娜？- 说
- Anna? - Yes.
你确定你要这么做？
Are you sure you want to do this?
你知道的 现在取消还不晚
We can still cancel everything, you know?
在我完全搞定之前我不能停
I can't stop until I get all the way out.
好的 我们按计划进行
Okay. We'll do as we planned.
我爱你
I love you.
我也爱你
I love you, too.
《非常人贩：重启之战》
(开门)
科技发展的太快了 对吧？
Technology moves so fast, doesn't it?
我是说 当你认为他们 做不了什么的时候
I mean, as soon as you think they can't come up with something,
他们就发明了其它的东西替代
they come up with something else.
很快车子就能自动驾驶了
It'll be able to drive itself soon.
让你怀疑我这样的人 是不是要淘汰了
Makes you wonder if guys like me will be out of it.
但是人们总是需要我这样的人 对吧？
But people always need guys like me, right?
把钥匙交出来 小子
Hand over the keys, boy!
[法语]
但是钥匙没有任何用处
But the keys won't do you any good.
你得知道 这辆车只能靠 驾驶员的指纹启动
See, this car only starts with the driver's unique fingerprints
只能由我开
when I grip the wheel.
闭嘴
Shut up!
你很聪明 说话尖刻 我要给你教训
You're smart and sharp. I'm gonna cut you up.
给我钥匙 然后滚
Gimme the keys and blow.
抱歉了
Excuse me.
[法语]
嘿
Hey!
你听着 事情这么办
Now, here's how we're going to do this.
手放在方向盘上 你开车
Put your hands on that wheel, and drive.
那可不是好计划
That's not a very good plan.
上车
Get in the car!
你会让我迟到的
You're gonna make me late.
我讨厌迟到
And I hate being late.
我说过那不是好计划…
I told you that wasn't a good plan.
(英国大使馆)
你迟到了
You're late.
只迟到了38秒
I'm 38 seconds late.
提前有很多程度 而迟到只有一种程度
There's several degrees of early and only one degree of late.
就是太迟了
And that's too late.
- 如何？- 什么如何？
- So? - So what?
事情怎么样？
So how'd it go?
我还以为你不会问问题
I thought you didn't ask questions.
我在工作的时候不会问问题 但这是捎带
I don't ask questions when I'm on a job, but this is a favor.
不错
Went okay.
那么你拿到了多少？
So how much did you get?
七百九十一
791.
791000美金？
791,000?
听起来你的收获可不错
That sounds like you did better than okay.
791欧元 那就是我从现在起的退休金
791 euros. That's my pension from here on.
每月791欧元
791 euros a month.
好吧…
Well...
退休快乐 老爸
Happy retirement, Dad.
三十年来一直领着可观的薪水 没有时间去花
Thirty-odd years of making good money and not a moment to spend it.
我现在有的是时间 还有足够的钱去花
Now I've got all the time in the world and not enough money to spend.
要我说 这个体制糟透了
If you ask me, the system's broken.
鸭肝泥
Pate de canard.
你觉得可以吗？
Good enough for you?
吃了之后告诉你
I'll tell you once I taste it.
也许你该考虑买一辆自己的车了
Maybe you should think about getting a car of your own, you know.
我有自己的车
I have my own car.
那你就应该考虑开它
Then maybe you should think about using it.
我很享受我们一起度过的品质时间
I enjoy our quality time together.
你应该知道我是靠开车为生的
You do realize I sit in traffic for a living.
你是做那个的吗？
Is that what you do?
我来这里是为接近你
I came here to be closer to you.
英国还不够近吗？
And England wasn't close enough?
你妈妈被葬在那里
Your mother's buried there.
对我而言 那地方现在就像个墓地
The island is like a cemetery to me now.
老爸 拜托你别太入戏
Easy on the drama, Dad, please.
你得答应我以后可别把我埋地下
Just promise me you won't stick me in the ground. Hmm?
你母亲是很好的天主教徒
Your mother was a good Catholic and everything,
但是当我死了之后
but when it comes my time to go,
只要把我火化 然后喂鱼
just throw me on the fire and feed me to the fish.
(匿名来电)
你要接电话吗 儿子？
You gonna get that, Junior?
我开车的时候不用手机
I don't use the phone while I'm driving.
∮ 这是一个很难时来运转的世界 ∮
∮ It's a hard world to get a break in. ∮
∮ 一切好东西都被占据 ∮
∮ All the good things have been taken. ∮
∮ 但是还有不少的方式看清 ∮
∮ But girl there are ways to make certain things pay. ∮
嗨 吉娜 是我 我们都在等你
Hi, Gina, it's me. We're all waiting for you.
请快点来
Please call me.
她会来的 别担心
She's gonna come. Don't worry.
你能相信这些姑娘吗？
Can you believe these girls?
她们表达感谢的方式
This is how they show their appreciation.
就是约会的时候迟到
By being late for an appointment.
你没听我说话
You don't listen to me.
这很粗鲁 如果我是顾客呢？
It's rude. What if I was a client?
那她就不会迟到了
She wouldn't be late then.
但是对于见我
But to meet me,
这个给她钱的人
the man who puts the money in her pockets
为她支付医疗费的人 她选择了迟到
and pays her medical bills, she's late.
肯定是她来了
I'm sure that's her.
最好是
It better be.
- 嗨 宝贝 - 抱歉 抱歉
- Hi, baby. - Sorry, sorry.
大家都很担心
Everyone was worried.
是的 这个地方的交通太糟了 我的手机也没电了
Yeah, traffic in this town's a nightmare and my cell phone died.
当我今晚见到卡拉索夫
Well, when I see Karasov tonight,
我会让他给你配个司机
I will tell him to get you a driver.
现在 既然我们都到了 我们就开始吧
Now, that we are all here, let's get this party going.
我也是这么想的
My sentiments exactly.
好的
Yes!
好的 好的
Okay. Okay.
她是谁？
Who is she?
我不知道 她自己干
I don't know. She was independent.
她死于吸毒过量
She died of a hero OD.
- 你拿到项链了？- 是的 做你的事去
- You got the necklace? - Yes. Do your thing.
好的
Okay.
- 乔 都好了吗？- 好了
- Qiao, ready? - Ready.
人人为我 我为人人
All for one, one for all.
我们走吧
Let's go.
那么 你有什么打算？
So, what's your plan?
什么打算？
My plan for what?
未来的打算 老爸
For the future, Dad.
你肯定有打算 你总是有打算
You must have a plan. You always have a plan.
好吧 我本来想把这个作为惊喜 但既然你问了
Well, I was gonna keep it as a surprise, but since you asked,
我在考虑买那个
I've been thinking about buying that.
对于领着工人退休金的人来说 这是条不错的渔船
That's a nice fishing boat for a guy with a worker's pension.
那是我的积蓄
I've been saving for it.
是的 我想你也很想旅行
Yeah, I think you miss to travel.
我是说 你之前就去过一些很不错的地方
I mean, you've been in some pretty wild places in your time.
80年代的德国
Germany in the '80s,
90年代的哥伦比亚 还有中东
Colombia in the '90s, Middle East since then.
依云水是个国际品牌 而我是…
Evian is a global brand, and I'm...
销售代表
Top sales rep.
是的
Yeah.
是的 我知道 是的
Yeah, I know. Yeah.
三十年来作为水务公司的销售
Thirty-odd years working as a rep for a water company,
你总是出现在那些最危险的地方
and you always seem to find yourself in the most dangerous places,
还恰好是关键时期
the most defining moments.
经历了柏林墙事件 还有制药企业
Fall of the Berlin Wall, collapse of the Medellin cartel.
- 还有塔利班 - 嗯
- And the Taliban... - Hmm.
别忘了塔利班
Don't forget the Taliban.
我相信费鲁杰的人很喜欢依云水
I bet they like Evian in Fallujah.
实际上 他们不太喜欢苏打水
Well, they don't really care for sparkling water.
他们更喜欢自来水
They do prefer the flat.
好的 爸爸
Okay, Dad.
儿子 我认为你对于我的谋生方式
Junior, I don't think you have one ounce of wiggle room
没有任何的评价权利
to moralize to me about how I earn my living.
- 你是什么意思？- 没什么
- And what you mean by that? - Oh, nothing.
我知道你的客户都是些影星
I'm sure all your clients are movie stars,
企业老板 达官贵人
captains of industry, dignitaries.
但我不会问 他们也不会说
I don't ask, they don't tell.
你应该知道些什么
That should tell you something.
(匿名来电)
看啊 匿名女士又来电了
Oh, look, um, Miss Unknown is calling again.
你为何认为这个人是个女的？
And what would make you think that "Unknown" is a Miss?
我只是猜猜
I'm just guessing.
喂？
Hello?
你是"玩命速递"？
Is this the Transporter?
那得看你是谁了
That depends who this is.
希望是你的下一个雇主
Hopefully, your next employer.
我不通过电话谈交易
I don't do business over the phone.
那就明天吧 下午两点 马杰斯酒店餐厅见
Tomorrow then. 2:00 p.m. at the bar at the Majestic hotel.
我怎么知道哪个人是你？
How will I know who you are?
我一个人
I'll be alone.
你知道 在我们那个年代 如果你想喝咖啡
You know, in my day, when you wanted to make a cup of coffee
你只需要烧水和磨咖啡豆
you just had to boil the water and strain the grinds.
现在还得要博士学位
Now it seems like you need a PhD.
爸爸 你是个博士
Dad, you have a PhD.
那是榨汁机
That's a juicer.
你这家里需要个女人
You need a woman around the house.
∮ 就像怀恨在心的人 ∮
∮ Acting like haters ∮
∮ 就和怀恨在心的人一样 ∮
∮ Haters acting like... Just, just acting like haters. ∮
∮ 重复我的话 我说的是仇恨者 ∮
∮ Yo, repeat my conversation I talk just 'bout my haters. ∮
∮ 因为他们喜欢我 ∮
∮ 'Cause haters love my pictures. ∮
∮ 所以我要大把撒钱 ∮
∮ So now I'm getting' funky Stackin' money off these hoes. ∮
∮ 仇恨者 就和仇恨者一样 ∮
∮ Haters actin' like... actin' like haters. ∮
∮ 重复我的话 我说的是仇恨者 ∮
∮ Yo, repeat my conversation I talk just about my haters. ∮
∮ 仇恨者喜欢我 ∮
∮ Them haters love my pictures. ∮
∮ 所以我要大把撒钱 ∮
∮ So now I'm getting' funky Stackin' money off these hoes. ∮
∮ 我是专业人士 ∮
∮ Any kind of cash I'm a professional. ∮
∮ 我是专业玩家 ∮
∮ When it come to ass I'm a professional. ∮
∮ 我是职业玩家 ∮
∮ When it's getting hot I'm a professional. ∮
∮ 杀光那些不服的家伙 ∮
∮ Murder alien slang Extraterrestrial. ∮
∮ 砰 砰 ∮
∮ Bang, bang. ∮
里奥？
Leo?
嗯？
Huh?
我们合作多久了？
Since when we work together?
12年了
Twelve years.
十五年
Fifteen.
Fifteen years.
你还是不相信我
You still don't trust me.
我相信你
I trust you.
但如果是涉及到女人的事情 我喜欢慢慢来
But when it comes to girls, I'd like to take my time.
慢慢来
Take your time.
- 那么尤里… - 嗯？
- And Yuri... - Hmm?
你现在真的住在自己的国度？
Is it true that you live in your plane now?
是的 没有海关 没有税收 自由的像个鸟儿
Yeah, no customs, no taxes, free like a bird, man.
- 等等 阿卡迪？- 现在不行
- Hold on. Arkady? - Not now.
出事了
There's been an accident.
说
Da.
他们说是因为电气故障
They're calling it an electrical malfunction.
他的妻子指认出了尸体
His wife identified the bodies.
那叫我来干嘛？
Then what am I doing here?
他是你的会计 难道不是吗？
He was your accountant, was he not?
是我的 也是其他很多人的会计
Mine and a lot of other people's.
你有把他们都找来看吗？
Did you ask all of them to come down here to see his body?
我不是叫你来看他的尸体
I didn't ask you to come here to see his body.
而是叫你来看她的尸体
I asked you to come here to see hers.
她是谁？
Who is she?
我还希望你告诉我
I was hoping you might tell me.
她显然是你的人
She appears to be one of yours.
我不明白你在说什么
I'm afraid I don't know what you're talking about.
这项链不是什么秘密 卡拉索夫先生
The Coeur Brise is hardly a secret, Mr. Karasov.
即使是我部门的人员 也和你的"女主人"打过交道
Even men in my own department have spent time with your "hostesses."
你是那么叫她们的 对吧？
That is what you call them, no?
我是个守法的生意人 警官
I'm a legitimate businessman, Inspector.
我手下有很多人为我工作
I have a lot of people who work for me.
我不可能全认识
And I can't possibly account for all of them.
这我理解 但我不明白为什么
Of course not. Though what I can't quite figure
她们中有人要杀你的会计
is why one of them would want to kill your accountant.
你刚才不是说 那是因为电气故障吗
I thought you said this was an electrical accident.
那是酒店的说法
That is what the hotel is saying.
她们没必要看到我们从
They haven't had the benefit of seeing the .9mm slugs
死者脑中取出的9毫米子弹
we pulled from their heads.
- 他们是被枪杀的？- 近距离射击
- They were shot? - At close range.
嫌疑人只不过想用火来掩盖痕迹
I suspect whomever did this started the fire to cover their tracks.
而你认为我与此有关
And you think I had something to do with it.
我只是想调查清楚
I want to be perfectly clear.
没有人指控你任何事
No one is accusing you of anything.
很好
Good.
因为如果那样的话 你最好多带点人
'Cause if you ever do, you better come with more men.
你认为那些95年的非洲人
You think the West Africans from '95
想要重新夺回地盘？
are trying to get back into the skin game?
- 他们没那么聪明 - 那是谁干的？
- They're too smart for that. - Who is then?
我不知道 但只要我知道是谁干的
I don't know. But when I find out who they are,
他们肯定会后悔在这世上
they'll wish they were someone else.
你找我
You called me.
你怎么知道是我？
How did you know it was me?
你说过你只有一个人
You said you'd be alone.
她就不是一个人？
Well, she's alone.
她还带着一条狗
Oh, she has a dog with her.
养狗的人一般会说他们带着狗
Dog people usually say they're with their dog.
我很高兴你能来见我 我是…
Well, I appreciate you coming to meet me. I am...
- 不需要名字 - 什么？
- No names. - What?
那是第一条规则
That's the first rule.
这样如果有人问起我你是谁 我就能说不知道
Someone asks me who you are, I have plausible deniability.
对我们都有好处
Better for me, better for you.
我听说你就是这样的人
I heard you were like this.
谁说的？
Heard from whom?
之前和你合作过的人
Someone you worked with previously
根据你的第一条规矩
whose name would presumably mean nothing
他的名字不重要
given your first rule.
你学得很快
You're a quick study.
还有什么我需要知道的规矩？
Are there any other rules I need to know about?
一旦条件和要求谈妥了 就不能改变
Once the deal is made, the deal never changes.
如果改变 我就不干了
You change the deal, I drive away.
你只要负责送一个人
The deal is for one passenger.
你接我上车 然后送我下车
You pick me up, drop me off.
你的威士忌 先生
Your whiskey, sir.
- 有行李吗？- 两个
- Any packages? - Two.
- 多重？- 总共104公斤
- Weight? - 104 kilos in total.
有问题吗？我听说你能送任何东西
Is that a problem? I was told that you can transport anything.
只要我不知道是什么就行 那是最后的规矩
As long as I don't know what it is. That's the last rule.
那不重要
Plausible deniability.
什么时候？
When's the pick up?
今晚五点 蒙特卡洛的摩纳哥银行
Tonight. 5:00 p.m. Banque de Monaco in Monte Carlo.
只有三个小时了
That's in three hours.
你难道要午睡吗？
You need to take a nap?
5:01我就走了 明白吗？
5:01 then I'm gone, clear?
好的
Yes.
我想我之前的雇主应该说过我的…
I gather my previous employer mentioned my...
当然 你的费用
Of course. Your fee.
先付一半 事成之后一半
Half now, half upon delivery.
我很会遵守规矩
I'm good at following the rules.
很好
Good.
如果一切顺利 也许我们将来还能合作
All goes well, perhaps we'll work together again in the future.
我们先别说的太早
Let's not get ahead of ourselves.
是我 他走了 你可以开始了
It's me. He left. You can proceed.
噢
Oh.
有问题吗？
Is there a problem?
不 这可是2005年产的
No, it's just that it's a Chateau Cheval Blanc
限量葡萄酒
from the 2005 vintage.
我知道 上面写了
I know, it says so on the label.
它卖900欧元
But it's 900 euros.
- 真的吗？- 是的
- Really? - Yeah.
900欧元？噢
900... 900 euros? Oop!
也许我可以为你推荐
Perhaps I can point you toward an excellent,
一些当地产的更适合的葡萄酒？
and more affordable selection of local vineyards?
不用了
I'll be fine.
(汽修厂)
弗兰克…
Frank...
你需要什么吗？
Do you need anything?
不 不用了 谢谢
No. I'm good, thanks.
你好 儿子
Hello, Junior.
爸爸 我想我今晚没法和你一起晚餐了
Dad, I don't think I'm going to be able to make dinner tonight.
我要处理一些事情
Couple of things I need to take care of.
真遗憾 我弄了瓶好酒
I'm sorry to hear that. I got us a really good bottle of wine.
是啊 很遗憾
Yeah, I'm sorry.
那我得找些人分享它
I'll just have to find someone else to share it with.
听起来不太好
That sounds like a good plan.
听起来妙极了
Sounds like a perfect idea.
需要我帮忙吗？
May I be of some assistance?
谢谢你
Thank you.
- 能帮我拿一下吗？- 当然
- Do you mind holding that? - Of course.
品味挺好
Expensive taste.
(摩纳哥银行)
发型不错
Nice hair.
我一直喜欢金发
Always wanted to be a blonde.
行李呢？
Where are the packages?
她们正在路上
They're coming.
十秒
Ten seconds.
五
Five.
一
One.
- 好的 都好了 - 搞什么？
- Okay, all set. - What's this?
- 什么？- 怎么回事？
- What? - What's going on?
你现在有问题了？
Oh, you're asking questions now?
不 我说过一旦谈妥 就不能改变
No. I told you once I set the deal, the deal doesn't change.
没有变 她们就是我的行李
And it hasn't. Here are my two lovely packages.
吉娜重49公斤 乔重55公斤 一共104公斤
Gina, 49 kilos, Qiao, 55 kilos. 104 in all.
我们得走了
We should go.
不 我要取消交易
No, I'm canceling the deal.
你得开车了
You should go.
你们马上下车
Out of the car. All of you. Now.
没人要下车 混蛋 马上开车
No one is getting out of the car, asshole. Now drive.
你认为这是第一次
You think this is the first time
有人用枪指着我的头吗？
someone's held a gun to my head?
我不这么想
No, I don't.
但这次会是第一次有人开枪
But it's gonna be the first time someone uses it.
她真可爱
Oh, she's a charmer.
安娜 有警察
Anna, there's a cop.
好的 我们没时间再讨论了
Okay, we don't have time to talk about this anymore.
给他看看吧
Just show it to him already.
给我看什么？
Show me what?
这样可不好
No good deed goes unpunished.
你可别搞砸了
Don't mess this up.
我是摩纳哥警察 请把窗户摇下来
Monaco Police. Vehicle documents, please.
窗户
Window!
你要怎么做 弗兰克？
What is it gonna be, Frank?
把窗户摇下来
Lower the window.
从车上下来
Get out of the vehicle!
系好安全带
Seatbelts, now.
让我爸爸接电话 我得马上和他谈谈
Get my father back on the phone. I want to talk to him now.
你会和他谈话的
You'll be able to talk to him all you want
你只要尽快把事情做完
as soon as the job is done.
哇
Whoo!
这是甩掉他们的好机会 弗兰克
This is a good time to lose them, Frank.
我已经尽力了
I'm doing my best.
你们为什么这么做？
So what's with all the getups?
又有问题了？
Questions again?
- 你的规矩呢？- 我没问名字
- What about your rules? - I don't ask names.
但如果有人绑架我得父亲 我就要问问题了
But when someone kidnaps my father, I ask questions.
我觉得你可以去拍商业片了 弗兰克
I guess you're as good as advertised, Frank.
谢谢
Thanks.
各单位注意… 代号3
All units... Code 3
目标是隧道里的黑色奥迪S8
black Audi S8 in the tunnel.
收到
Copy!
听着 我会把你们送到目的地
Look, you'll be delivered as promised,
但如果我父亲有什么事情…
but if anything happens to my dad...
别分心 亲爱的 你父亲会没事的
Stay focused, honey. Your father will be fine.
那是什么？
What's that?
更多警察来了
More company.
小心
Watch out.
没开玩笑吧
You weren't kidding.
我不喜欢开玩笑
Kidding's not really my thing.
- 好的 我们走 -怎么了？
- Okay, let's go. - What are we doing?
我们得换车 走吧
We need to change cars. Come on.
我们走
Let's go.
我们要把车留下当证据吗？
Are we going to leave the car with all the evidence?
不是的
Not really.
说实话 这真的很奇怪
It's really quite strange, to tell you the truth.
地中海银行之前是被打劫过
The Mediterranean Bank has been robbed before,
但从未遇到过这样的事情
but never like this.
你来看
Let me show you.
你会看到一个女人
You'll see a woman right there.
她自称艾琳娜·图金
She said she was Elena Turgin,
是斯坦尼斯拉夫·图金的妻子
wife of one Stanislav Turgin.
有护照 还有他的保险箱钥匙
Had a passport and his safety deposit box's keys
证明是真的
to prove as much.
那不是艾琳娜·图金
That's not Elena Turgin.
是的
Yes.
虽然当时我并不知道
And while I didn't know that at the time,
但我依然拒绝了她
I refused to allow her access nonetheless.
因为只有图金先生可以使用
As only Mr. Turgin is authorized.
但如你所见 我被挟持了
But as you will see, I was coerced.
第一个姑娘拿走了我的钥匙
First girl took my keys.
有了这两样东西 她就能自己打开保险箱
With both sets, she could open the security box by herself.
我已经无法阻止她了
There was nothing I could do to stop her.
当时是谁在看守？
And who was on the security post?
嗯
Hmm.
就是他
Voila.
她们看起来都是一样的 你无法区分开
They all look exactly the same. You cannot tell them apart.
还有一事
There's one more thing.
逃跑的司机
Getaway driver.
他接上了一个女孩
He picked the one girl up,
然后又等了一会 接上了另外两个
and then waited for the two others to arrive moments later.
警察找到了那辆车和车里剩下的东西
The police found the car, what was left of it.
那辆车被烧过了 不过他们已经不见了
It was set fire to, but they were already gone.
那当然
Of course they were.
抱歉
Oh. Excuse me.
喂？我马上来
Yes? I'll be right there.
是尼斯的一个探员
An inspector from Nice.
你们在这等我一会儿 我马上回来
If you'll wait for me just a minute, I'll be right back.
你怎么看？
What do you think?
她们不是我们要找的女孩
They're either our girls,
或是某个人想让我们以为她们就是
or someone who's trying to pass themselves off as our girls.
我会去查查存货 调查一下我们的对手
I will do an inventory and check with the competition.
看看是否有下落不明的
See if there's anyone unaccounted for.
先是图金在酒店 现在又出这事？
First Turgin at the hotel, and now this?
别担心 我们会查清楚是谁 并让他付出代价
Don't worry. We will find who and make him pay.
又迟到了 儿子
Late again, Junior.
儿子？
Junior?
你还好吧 爸爸？
You're okay, Dad?
我这辈子栽在过很多混蛋手里
Well, I've been sucker punched a lot in my time,
但从没栽在过一个女孩手里
but never by a girl.
站在那儿
Stop right there.
你们还有多少人？
How many more of you are there?
她是最后一个
She's the last one.
她是爱沙尼亚 来自塔林
She is Estonian. From Tallinn.
我可以告诉你 我去过那 做过一些很胡来的事
I've done some funky shit in my time down there, I can tell you.
事实上 他们那的伏特加非常非常棒
Actually they've got very, very good vodka.
好极了 爸爸
That's great, Dad.
如果我有武器 你早就知道了
If I were armed, you'd know it by now.
看来他真是你爸
Your father sure is.
他没问题了
He's clean.
这是我们还欠你的
Here's the rest of what we owe you.
非常感谢
Thank you very much.
现在可以解开他了吧 我们再也不会见到你们
Now if you'll untie him so we can leave and never see you again.
恐怕我做不到
I'm afraid I can't do that.
我们跟你们还没完
We're not done with you just yet.
我真失望 我以为你们都是天生的金发女郎
I'm disappointed. I thought you were all natural blondes.
你们想要什么？
What do you want?
我想做一笔新交易
I wanna make a new deal.
谢谢 不过我没兴趣
Thanks, but I think I'll pass.
你还没听我说的条件呢
You haven't heard the terms yet.
那一定很好
This should be good.
非常简单
They're really very simple.
我们要去拜访一个人
We're going to pay someone a visit,
而你要确保让我们抵达那里
and you're going to make sure that we get there and back
并且毫发无损地回来
without any more incidents.
我没看出这对我来说有什么好处
I'm not sure I see how much of a deal that really is for me.
好处就是你爸爸可以活下去
The deal for you is that your father gets to live.
我不答应 你会枪毙他？
So you're gonna shoot him?
然后呢？你们还是得对付我
Then what? You still have me to contend with.
你们觉得我们很蠢吗 弗兰克？
You think we're stupid, Frank?
你真让我伤心
That hurts my feelings.
我要是你就不会去碰 那玩意只要一碰到你的皮肤
I wouldn't do that if I were you. That touches your skin,
那和你父亲啤酒里的毒性差不多大
it's nearly as toxic as the dose your father drank in his beer.
头疼 呕吐 抽搐
Headaches, vomiting, convulsions,
这一切症状最终导致死亡
all leading up to an eventual death.
别固执了 那毒会在12小时内发作
Soup to nuts, it will kill a man in 12 hours.
我应该现在杀了你们 你们所有人
I should kill you right now. All of you.
可以啊
You could do that,
不过这样 你得让你爸爸跟我们一起死
but you'd be killing your father along with us.
而实验室起码要花12个小时 才能搞清那是什么毒
It will take the lab more than 12 hours to find out what it is.
你们有解药？
And you have the antidote?
你继续玩 你爸爸就能拿到解药
You play ball, your father gets it.
不玩 他就死
You don't, he dies.
我怎么知道你不会反悔？
How do I know you're gonna hold up your end of the bargain?
我对你撒过谎吗？
Did I ever lie to you?
另外 你也没什么选择
Besides, you don't have much of a choice.
我找来了 所有和视频中相像的女孩
I got all the girls that most fit the description on the video.
她们都在这了？
They're all here?
都在这 除了4个
All but four.
这么说 她们当中一个就是酒店里身亡的女孩
So one of them is the dead girl from the hotel.
其他的就是我们的内贼
And the others are our thieves.
她们从保险箱里到底拿到了什么？
What did they get from the safe deposit box?
一些现金 珠宝 文件
Some cash, jewelry, documents.
我只知道 图金没有留太多财物在那
Far as I know, Turgin didn't leave very much in there.
但那个司机还是无法解释
Still doesn't explain the driver.
你认识他 不是吗？
You know him, don't you?
我们是老相识了
We go way back.
- 说 - 抱歉打搅您了 先生
- Da. - Excuse me for disturbing you, sir.
不过 有几个警察乘着快艇过来了
But there are police officers approaching the yacht.
跟他们说我在开会
Tell them I'm in a meeting.
接通马索夫和尤里的电话
Get Imasov and Yuri on the phone.
毕竟 这不是最糟的方法
All in all, it's not the worst way to go.
我一直觉得我最终会被人开枪打死 在某处腐烂
I always thought I'd end up being shot. Left to rot somewhere.
抱歉 但我们现在算是搭档了
Excuse me, but now we're partners,
也许你可以告诉我 这一切是为了什么
maybe you can tell me what this is all about?
你照我们说的做
You do what we ask,
我想你会发现 越冒险 你的收获越大
I think you'll find that the more you venture, the more you will gain.
大仲马的名言？
Quoting Alexandre Dumas?
什么意思？你是达尔达尼央
Like, what? You're Count D'Artagnan
而他们是"三个火枪手"？
and they're the Three Musketeers?
你看过啦
You've read it.
事实上 我最喜欢的台词是:"我知道你是个好人
In fact, my favorite line is, "I'm sure you're very nice,
不过 你如果别来烦我就更好"
but you'd be nicer if you left me alone."
没门 孩子 帮我拉上
No deal, Junior. Zip me up.
嗯 别这么难过的表情
Mmm. Don't look so sad.
24小时后 一切都将结束
In 24 hours, this will all be over.
一旦你明白了我们的目的
And once you understand what we're up to,
你甚至可能会喜欢它
you might even like it.
就停在这
Stop right here.
我们来这干什么？
What are we doing here?
你想不想演医生？
Do you wanna play doctor?
你为克尔效命了多长时间？
How long have you been working for the Coeur Brise?
我看见了你的项链
I saw your necklace.
从12岁起
Since I was 12.
我想你现在明白了 我是怎么认识你以前的雇主了吧
I suppose now you understand how I know your former employer.
卡拉索夫 事实上我们当时 并没拿出最佳的表现
Karasov. We didn't exactly leave things on the best of terms.
我很惊讶 他还推荐了我
I'm surprised he'd recommend me.
他没有
He didn't.
不过我在很多场合下偷听到
But I overheard him on plenty of occasions
其他那些人说 你是最厉害的
telling other people that you're the best.
被世界上最差的人称之为最好的
Called the best by one of the worst on the planet.
我不确定那是种什么感觉
I'm not sure how to feel about that.
喂 现在麻醉科哪个医生在值班？
Hello, who's the anesthesiologist on call?
应该是本尼特医生
That would be Dr. Benet.
好的 你能帮我转接到总机吗？
Right, of course. Can you connect me with central supply, please?
- 总机 - 我是史密斯医生 呼叫本尼特医生
- Central supply. - Yeah, I'm Dr. Smith, calling for Dr. Benet.
我们要给一个美国公民做手术
We're gonna be operating on a US citizen
我们的OR-6用完了
and we're running low on Neroflurax in OR-6.
我会派人送去
I'll send someone up.
不用麻烦了 我已经在路上了
Yeah, don't bother, I'm already on my way.
- 史密斯医生？- 是我
- Dr. Smith? - That's me.
OR-6 请在这签字
Neroflurax. You sign here.
- 我这就给你拿 - 好极了
- I'll grab it. - Perfect.
我还需要你在这盖章
But I also need your stamp right here.
好 当然
Okay, sure.
行了
Done!
我们走
Let's go.
没事吧？
Everything okay?
再来杯伏特加吗？
Another shot of vodka?
当然
Sure.
你的口音是哪的？南欧人？
Your accent, what is it? Meridional?
你听得出是南欧的？
You can tell it's meridional?
现在已经很少听到朗格多克口音了
Well, you don't get to hear the Languedoc much these days
除了一些偏远的乡下
except from rural old farts.
他们很喜欢他们的奥克西唐语
They love their Occitan.
我父母来自巴斯克地区
My parents are from the Basque Country...
- 比利牛斯山 - 比利牛斯山
- In the Pyrenees. - The Pyrenees.
我很了解巴斯克地区
I know the Basque country well.
你是怎么知道的？
How do you know it?
不是有家大型的航空航天工业基地就建造在那吗？
Was a big aerospace industry tucked in all around there.
弹头 涡轮直升机
Warheads, helicopter turbo shafts...
我去过很多地方 中东各地都去过
I ran many sorts of parts to all sorts of places in the Middle East.
巴斯克人都很好
Basque people are good people.
我很喜欢巴斯克的鸡肉
I love that poulet basquaise.
你会做菜吗？
You cook?
当然
Sure.
你呢？
And you?
当然
But of course.
他们拿到气体了 我们该上了
They got the gas. We're up.
他们拿到气体了
They got the gas.
他们拿到气体了 好
They got the gas. Okay.
你们有谁会说英语吗？
Any of you speak English?
不 不 不会
No, no, no.
你们有谁想赚一千欧元吗？
Any of you want to make a thousand euros?
有哇 当然
Yeah. Sure!
走
Let's go.
- 嗨 - 嗨
- Hi. - Hi.
喝一杯怎么样？
How about a drink?
去你房间里喝怎么样？
How about your room?
他们是怎么抢到银行的？
How the hell did they rob a bank?
他们必须得有他的…
They'd have to have his...
他有 他们有 某个人有
He did. They did. Someone did.
我已经通知了所有人
I'm calling everyone.
在我查清这件事之前
Until I figure out what's going on,
你注意一下有没有奇怪的事发生 好吗？
be on the look out for anything strange. Okay?
好
Okay.
打电话给飞行员 咱们离开这
Call the pilot. Let's get out of here.
我们不能起飞 太晚了
We can't take off. It's too late.
我希望在规则允许范围内起飞
I want to be on the wheels up the minute regulations allow.
是 先生
Yes, sir.
请随意
Please, make yourself comfortable.
不 你请随意
No, you make yourself comfortable.
脱下衣服
Get undressed.
(满月俱乐部)
请系好安全带
Seatbelts, please.
3个女孩穿一样的衣服抢银行 没人知道谁是谁
Three girls dressed the same to rob a bank so no one knows who's who.
你是在问我还是在跟我说话？
Are you asking me or telling me?
你看 我不明白的一件事是
See, the thing I can't figure out is
你们当中为什么有一个不来 错过这一切的乐趣？
why one of you stays behind and misses out on all the fun.
在《三个火枪手》里 其实是4个人
In The Three Musketeers, there were really four.
我们中必须留下一个 看着你亲爱的老爹
One of us had to stay behind and look after dear old dad.
不 不 我不这么想
No. No, I don't think that's it.
你们可以把他五花大绑的
You could have left him tied up in the boot.
也许我们比三个火枪手更聪明
Maybe we're smarter than the Three Musketeers.
如果你说他"老" 那就说明你不聪明
You're not that smart if you're calling him "old."
嘿 滚 不能在这停车
Hey, jerk-off! You can't park here!
我去换气罐 然后在这等你们 好吗？
I'll swap the tanks and we meet back here, okay?
快点 咱们开工吧
Come on. Let's do this.
(满月俱乐部)
嘿 你 你在干什么？
Hey, you! What you think you're doing?
我来换新气
I got you fresh smoke.
但是有人刚换过了啊
But the guy just changed the tanks.
那气体都过期了 这标签上有警告的 看
It's expired. There's a warning right on the label. Look.
他身体不舒服
He wasn't feeling well.
能把钥匙给我吗？
Can you give me the key?
嘿
Hey!
滚
Go!
我去弄指纹
I get the fingerprints.
我放哨
I'll keep an eye out.
- 来 帮我一下 - 好
- Okay, help me. - Okay.
就这
Right there.
- 他们都晕过去了 - 好
- They're all out. - All right.
很好
Good.
(请输入账户的后6位数字)
好了 宝贝 要来了
Okay, baby, it's coming.
好 我进去了
All right, I'm in.
希望这号码是对的
I hope the transfer code works.
咱们会知道的 好 试试看
We're gonna find out. All right. Let's try.
可以了
Here we go.
好 稳住
Okay, hold on.
(转账完成)
好 都妥了 我们走
Yes! All good. Come on, let's go!
快离开这
Let's get the hell out of here.
该死
Shit.
他去哪了？
Where the hell is he?
喂？
Yes?
让女士们在阴暗的角落里等着 可不是什么好事
It's not nice to keep ladies waiting alone in a dark alley.
不管你指的是哪些女士 告诉她们我在路上了
Whoever those ladies are, tell them I'm on my way.
好
All right.
嘿 你早该给我钥匙的
Hey, you should have just given me the key.
- 他在哪？- 我不知道
- Where is he? - I don't know!
他去喝茶了还是怎么样？
Is he drinking tea or what?
你怎么耽误了这么久？
What took you so long?
有几个孩子需要我哄睡着
There was a couple of babies I had to put to sleep.
该死 看来这些孩子又醒了
Shit! Seems some of the babies just woke up.
而且他们看起来都很暴躁
And they look cranky.
快点 我们走
Come on, let's go.
在这等我
Wait for me here.
什么都别碰
And don't touch anything.
什么？
What?
他要去哪？
Where is he going?
- 该死 - 安娜 让车停下
- Shit! - Anna, stop the car!
他说什么都别碰
He said don't touch anything.
好吧 他可以的 他可以的
Okay, he's got this. He's got this!
- 吉娜 - 我不知道我能否信任这个人 安娜
- Gina! - I don't know if I trust this guy, Anna!
该死
Oh, shit.
不 我觉得咱们现在该踩刹车了
No, I think we should hit the brakes now.
不 他说了什么都别碰
No, he said don't touch anything. No!
安娜
Anna!
停车
Stop the car!
安娜 快点
Anna, do it now!
- 我不能 - 我可以试试
- I can't do it! - I can try.
踩刹车 那门
Hit the brakes! The gate!
快点
Hurry up!
- 坐稳了 - 天呐
- Hold on tight. - Oh, God.
不 不
No! No!
真的吗？
Seriously?
我们要迟到了 我爸爸不喜欢我迟到
We're late. My dad hates it when I'm late.
我们在等什么 都早上6点了
What are we waiting for? It's almost 6:00 a.m.
机长在路上了 尤里先生
Well, the captain's on his way, Mr. Yuri.
我们等条件一允许就起飞
We'll be off as soon as regulations permit.
老天
Oh, God.
早上好 先生
Good morning, sir!
早上好 尤里先生
Good morning, Mr. Yuri.
你们是谁？
Who are you?
我是你的飞行员 马丁内机长
I'm your pilot, Captain Martinet.
代替盖东机长的？
Captain Guesdon's replacement.
这是怎么回事？
What the hell is this?
真尴尬 我以为他跟你说了
Well, this is embarrassing. I'd assumed that he told you.
他病了 食物中毒 牡蛎 我记得他是这么说的
Um, he's sick. Food poisoning. Oysters, I believe he said.
打电话给他
Call him up.
喂 尤里先生
Hello, Mr. Yuri.
我听说你病了 盖东
I'm told you are sick, Guesdon.
是的 牡蛎
Yes, oysters.
有个飞行员来替你了 是你让他来的吗？
The pilot who has come in your stead, you vouch for him?
是的 我特别推荐他
Yes, I highly recommend him.
他是个很好的飞行员
He is a decorated pilot.
好吧 祝你好起来
Okay, well, feel better.
谢谢
Thank you.
我希望可以尽快起飞
I want to be in the air as soon as possible.
我们会尽全力的 先生
We shall do our very best, sir.
我是机长 我们可以起飞了吗
This is the captain speaking, we are cleared for take-off.
早上好 天空之星669
Good morning, Air Star 669.
请等候起飞指令
Please wait for take-off clearance.
要喝点什么吗 尤里先生？
Would you like something to drink, Mr. Yuri?
香槟？橙汁？
Champagne? Orange juice?
那个 香槟吧
Ah, well, champagne is good.
香槟 马上来
Champagne, coming right up.
走开 就留我们俩
Leave us. Go away.
你的香槟 尤里先生
Your champagne, Mr. Yuri.
谢谢
Thank you.
你还需要别的吗？
Would you like anything else?
对 让机长抓紧起飞
Yeah, tell the pilot to get a move on
然后过来陪我喝酒
and then come and keep me company.
没问题
Sure.
电路板检查
Electrical board checked,
阻尼器检查 操作器检查
yaw dampers on and operating.
方向舵微调检查
Rudder trimmer checked.
准备好了就能起飞了 机长
Ready when you are, Captain.
前往主跑道
Proceed to main runway.
早上好 我是机长
Good morning, this is the captain speaking again.
我们现在在3号跑道 准备起飞
We are third in line for take-off.
请系好安全带
Please fasten your seat belts.
我们将马上升空
We should be in the air momentarily.
终于
Finally.
怎么回事？
What the hell?
喂？
Hello?
嗯
Hmm.
3-1-0-5
3-1-0-5.
太好了
Yes!
天空之星669
Air Star 669.
请前往主跑道
Please make your way to the main runway.
等候跑道清理再起飞
And wait to be cleared for take-off.
谢谢 空中交通管制台
Thank you, Air Traffic Control.
哦 等等 我们有警报
Oh, hang on. We have an alert.
可能是保险丝烧断了
It's probably just a blown fuse.
Probably just a blown fuse?
难道你还坐在那张该死的椅子上
It's no wonder you're still in that bloody chair!
天空之星669呼叫塔台 我们必须…
Air Star 669 to tower. We're gonna have to run...
搞定了 下飞机吧
We're good. Let's get off this plane.
天空之星669呼叫塔台…
Air Star 669 to tower...
这里是塔台 收到吗？
Tower to Air Star 669, do you copy?
重复 收到吗？
I repeat, do you copy?
这边
This way!
塔台呼叫天空之星669 请保持原位
Tower to Air Star 669, hold your position!
尤里先生 你那边还好吗？尤里先生？
Mr. Yuri! Everything okay in there? Mr. Yuri?
先生
Sir!
我跟你的朋友吉娜聊过
I was talking to your friend Gina.
在巴斯克地区有一个巨大的 航空航天工业基地
There's a huge aerospace industry in the Pays Basque region.
什么？
What?
在比利牛斯山
In the Pyrenees.
别管了 当我没说
Don't worry. Never mind!
立刻呼叫保安
Call security immediately.
别说迟到
Don't say it.
你怎么能迟到
How can you be late?
你是什么特种兵？
What kind of Special Forces were you?
你在哪 爸爸？
Where are you, Dad?
听着 现在很复杂 儿子 我们被困住了
Listen, there's been a complication, son. We're trapped.
我们现在在货物区
We're in the main compartment cargo area.
你有办法让我们逃出去吗？
Do you have any idea how to get us out of here?
你是面朝着前轮的吗？
Are you towards the front wheel?
不 不 是货物区
No, no, it's the main cargo hatch.
停下飞机 重复 停下飞机
Stop the plane! I repeat, stop the plane!
从后面爬上去
Climb in the back.
我需要你为我数数
I'm gonna need you to count for me.
好 我数到5 你就跳
Okay, I'm going to count to five and you're going to jump.
你说跳是什么意思？
What do you mean, jump?
什么？不 我们不能跳
What? No! We can't jump!
儿子
Junior!
- 5 - 5
- Five! - Five!
- 4 - 4
- Four! - Four!
- 3 - 3
- Three! - Three!
- 2 - 2
- Two! - Two!
- 1 - 1
- One! - One!
有多严重？
How bad is it?
非常严重
It's really bad!
用丝巾 用力按住伤口
Take the scarf and put pressure on it!
不行 我们需要医生
It's not working, we need a doctor.
如果我们不能甩掉这些人
If we don't outrun these guys,
我们还需要一个非常好的律师
we're gonna need a bloody good lawyer too.
塔台呼叫天空之星669 你们要撞机了
Tower to Air Star 669, you are going to crash.
收到吗？669 收到吗？
Do you copy? 669, do you copy?
重复 你们要撞机了
I repeat, you are going to crash.
你需要立即停止引擎
You need to stop the engine right now!
- 醒醒 - 如果你们听见了
- Wake up! - If you hear me,
你需要立刻拉下紧急刹车
you need to pull the emergency brake!
就是你右边的把手
It's the trigger on your right.
- 对 对 我看见了 - 现在就拉
- Yeah, yeah, I see it. - Do it now!
- 她在抽搐 - 我们怎么办？
- She's convulsing! - What do we do?
你们抱紧她
You hold on!
- 看见那栋楼了吗 儿子？- 看见了
- You see the building, Junior? - I do.
好 飞机会动 但楼不会动
Well, planes tend to move, buildings tend to stand still.
- 我就是这么想的 - 不 不 不
- That's what I'm counting on. - No, no, no, no!
我就知道你在想什么
I see what you're thinking.
- 然后呢？- 我很讨厌
- And? - I hate it!
- 老天… - 怎么会？
- Holy... - What the hell?
身份不明的汽车 刚进入了主要过道
The unidentified vehicle has just entered the main terminal.
快点
Come on!
弗兰克
Frank!
(我被抢劫了)
- 好 稳住 - 好 好
- Okay, hold on. - Yeah, okay.
你得帮帮她
You gotta help her.
别看我 我这部分已经完成了
Don't look at me. I did my part.
我送你们去了那 也回来了 现在 把解药给我
I got you there and back. Now, give me the antidote.
弗兰克
Frank!
她已经流干血了
She can bleed out for all I care.
儿子
Junior!
交易一旦达成 就不会再变
Once the deal is set, the deal doesn't change.
交易内容是 现在我该拿解药了
The deal was my time for the antidote.
根本没有解药
There is no antidote!
什么？
Excuse me?
不过是水
It's just water in the vial.
他酒里什么都没放 我们骗你的
There's nothing in his beer. We made it up.
这么说他不会死咯？
So he's not gonna die?
不会是被毒死的
Not from poison.
亲爱的 给我拿点布条和水过来 好吗？
Be a dear and get me some rags and water, would you?
看 子弹还在那
Look, the bullet is still in there.
如果我们不弄出来 血就止不住
If we don't get it out and the bleeding doesn't stop
她会死的
she is gonna die.
好吧 我们在来的路上已经浪费了足够多的时间了
All right, we've wasted enough time getting here already.
我们都说好了 不去找医生
We all agreed. No doctors.
不 不 我们不能让她死
No. No, we can't just let her die.
我们知道那样会很危险
We knew it would be dangerous.
好 不找医生 咱们自己帮她
Okay, no doctors. Let's help her ourselves.
能把那瓶子递给我吗？
Can you pass me that bottle, would you?
爸爸 你…
Dad, you...
爸爸 不行
Dad, you can't...
别担心 儿子 这是让我提神的
Don't worry, son. It's focus for me.
好 水来了
Okay, here's the water.
谢谢 宝贝
Oh, thanks, love.
"宝贝"？
"Love"?
你知道 她来自比利牛斯山 巴斯克区
You know, she's from Pays Basque. Pyrenees.
爸爸 那太好了 爸爸
Dad, that's great, Dad.
能找点东西把她的腿抬高吗？
Can you get something to raise her leg up, please.
看看能不能找到香水
See if you can find some perfume,
镊子 还有糖之类的
some tweezers and if there's any sugar around.
好
Okay.
你想让我做点什么？
What do you want me to do with it?
好吧 从衣服上撕点碎布条
All right. Take the rod off one of those clothes racks
然后缠在末端
and wrap this around the end.
做什么？为什么？
What to do? To do what?
然后去弄这房子里的蜘蛛网
And swab all the corners of the room.
看看能弄到多少蜘蛛网
See how many cobwebs you can get on there.
- 蜘蛛网？- 没错
- Cobwebs? - S'il vous plait.
给
Here.
你这辈子处理过很多类似的伤吗？
You handle a lot of triage in your time as a sales rep?
我该怎么说呢 依云山的那些孩子们
What can I tell you? Those boys at Evian,
他们很彪悍
they play rough.
你可以用伏特加
You could use the vodka.
别胡闹了 儿子 那是浪费好的伏特加
Don't be ridiculous, son. That's a waste of good vodka.
好 听着 她看起来也许昏迷了
Right, now listen. She may look like she's out cold, right?
但她还是能感觉到疼痛的 我要你按住她
But she's gonna feel this. I need you to hold her down.
- 好 - 行啦
- Okay. - All right.
抱歉 玛利亚 不过这是唯一的办法
Sorry about this, Maria, but it is the only way.
- 找到了吗？- 就…
- You got it? - It's...
快点拿蜘蛛网来
Hurry with the cobwebs!
好 谢谢
All right, thanks.
这有什么用？
What does that do?
糖能为伤口杀菌 蜘蛛网能凝结伤口
The sugar disinfects the wound and cobwebs coagulate the blood.
这不是克利夫兰医学中心
It's not exactly the Cleveland Clinic,
不过这能让我们在治好她之前
but it's going to keep her alive
让她活下去
until we get her patched up properly.
用力按住 好吗 儿子？
Put some pressure on that, would you, Junior?
你没事了 你没事了
You're okay. Shh, you're okay.
今天不会有人死的
No one's dying today.
看看那是谁
Look who's there.
同样的女孩 不同的衣服
Same girls, different outfits.
这是怎么发生的？
How did this happen?
一秒钟前一切都还正常
One second everything is fine,
接着我就从地板上醒来了
the next I wake up on the floor.
是某种医用麻醉剂
It's some kind of medical grade anesthetic.
他们换掉了烟雾机的气筒
They switched the tank for the fog machine.
我不明白的一点是
One part I can't quite figure out though is
你的女孩为什么要抢劫我
why your girls would rob me.
别胡扯了
Don't be ridiculous.
我听说她们还抢劫了图金的银行保险箱
Just the same as I heard they robbed Turgin's safe deposit box.
你不能觉得我和这事有关联
You can't think I had anything to do with this.
我不知道该怎么想
I'm not sure what to think.
不过好像是有另一个人在跟她们合作
But it appears that someone else is working with them.
我没记错的话 你是认识他的
You and he know each other, if I recall.
是尤里
It's Yuri.
说
Da.
当然没有
Of course not.
我会查到底
I'll get to the bottom of it.
尤里也被袭击了 又是一个克尔
Yuri got hit as well. Another Coeur Brise.
非常方便 你不觉得吗
Awfully convenient, don't you think?
我们两个人被你的女孩
Two of us get robbed by your girls
还有存在于你过去幻觉中的人抢劫了
and a friend from your illustrious past.
给我6小时 我会找到他们处理好
Give me six hours. I'll find them and I'll take care of it.
我们走
Let's go.
破了吗
Are they broken?
还碰到过更糟糕的情况
They've been worse.
让我看看
Let me see.
没事的
I'll be okay.
你爸爸怎么样
What about your dad?
看来她们在补偿他
Looks like they made it up to him.
我已经记不清 她们上次是什么时候
I can't remember the last time either of them
跟付钱的男人同床了
slept in the same bed as the men who pay them.
他应该没付钱
I don't think he paid.
好吧…
Well...
还有别的吗
Something else?
是的
Yes.
我想感谢你为我们做的一切
I wanted to thank you for what you've done for us.
对不起毒药的事我骗了你
I'm sorry I lied to you about the poison.
要不先为一开始绑架我爸爸道个歉？
How about being sorry you kidnapped my father in the first place?
那我也很抱歉
I'm sorry about that, too.
利用你爸爸是我的错
It was wrong for me to use your father,
而且利用你也是我的错
and it was wrong for me to use you.
大错特错
Very wrong.
我想我们的交易完成了
I think our deal is done.
对
Yeah.
你想不想知道我接下来要做什么？
Don't you want to know what I'm going to do next?
我有个好主意
I think I have a good idea.
我说的是将来
I'm talking about the future.
跟我说说将来
Tell me about the future.
我会完成我们开始的事情
I'm going to finish what we started.
你怎么会被卷进来的
How did you get caught up in all of this?
我来自一个贫穷的小村庄
I come from an impoverished village.
酒精和毒品杀死了那些枪都杀不死的人
Drinking and drugs killed the people that guns didn't.
然后我12岁时
And then when I was 12,
我从工作的工厂回到家
I came home from the factory where I worked
我妈妈把我介绍给一个衣冠整洁的人
and my mother introduced me to a man in a very nice suit.
卡拉索夫
Karasov.
他说我可以去温暖的地方 为他工作
He said I could come and do work for him in warm places.
他会给我食物和衣服
He would give me food and clothes
把我介绍给别的人赚钱
and introduce me with men for money.
我看着我妈 她说没关系
I looked at my mom and she said it was okay.
"好 去吧"
"Yeah, go."
我就去了
And so I did.
不久之后我才发现 她把我卖给了他
It wasn't until later that I found out that she sold me to him.
才500美元
For $500.
天啊 安娜
Jesus, Anna.
我觉得她起码应该要600 对吧
I think she could have gotten $600, right?
你不需要这样做的 你知道的
You don't need to do this, you know.
你还是可以离开
You can still walk away.
如果现在收手 我所经历的一切
If we stop now, it will have been for nothing,
都会变成徒劳
everything I went through.
你知道被当做垃圾
Do you know what it feels like
是什么感觉吗
to be thought of as trash?
你知道他会杀了你
He'll kill you, you know.
不会有任何犹豫
Without thinking about it.
就像伯爵对火枪手说的
It's like the Count said to his Musketeers,
"我奋斗一生不是为了害怕死亡的"
"I don't cling to life sufficiently to fear death."
爸爸 该走了
Dad. Time to go.
真的？
Really?
- 不好意思 女士们 - 呣 呣
- Excuse me, ladies. - Mmm. Mmm.
∮ 因为在你面前我是笨蛋 ∮
∮ 'Cause I'm a fool for you. ∮
∮ 你知道我说的是实话 ∮
∮ You know I speak the truth. ∮
∮ 无论你说什么做什么 ∮
∮ Whatever you say or do. ∮
你知道她们在干另一件活
You know they're doing another job.
对 对付俄国犯罪团伙老大 是个自杀式任务
Yeah, taking on a Russian crime lord is more of a suicide mission.
想像一下做那种事以后 你的生活会变得多么糟糕
Imagine how horrible your life has to be to try something like that.
我在糟糕的地方 见过很多不好的事情
I've seen some horrible things in some horrible places.
被卖作妓女 死亡是唯一的出路
Being sold into prostitution with death as your only out.
那才是最糟糕的
That's about as bad as it gets.
问题是 你打算怎么做
The question is, what are you gonna do about it?
我？
Me?
这车上又没别人
There's no one else in the car.
我不用做任何事
I don't have to do anything.
送你回家 把车扔掉换上直升机
I'm gonna drop you home, ditch the car at a chopper,
去巴黎待一段 等风头过去
go to Paris for a bit until things cool down, you know.
听起来不像我养大的人
That doesn't sound like the man I raised.
爸爸 行了
Dad, stop.
好吧 别太过分
All right, stay within the lines,
注意所有细节 那才是我们这样的人该做的
watch everything play out, that's exactly what a fobbit would do.
我这辈子都只想做正确的事
Look, my entire life, I've tried to do the right thing, you know.
也许我不是你这样的间谍
Maybe I wasn't a spy like you,
但我为那蠢货工作过
but I served that fool.
可我得到了什么？
What did it get me?
我完全不应得的下场 这是你自己说的
Shit I didn't deserve. You said it yourself.
但这不代表你不应该做正确的事
It doesn't mean you stop doing the right thing.
到了巴黎给我寄张明信片
Send me a postcard from Paris.
- 爸爸？- 你好 弗兰克
- Dad? - Hello, Frank.
别跟我说你听不出我的声音 又没隔多久
Don't tell me you don't recognize my voice. It hasn't been that long.
你想要什么？
What do you want?
我想做个交易
Well, I want to make a deal.
你有我要的人 准确来说是三个人
You have some people I want, three of them to be exact,
而我有你要的东西 来吧 问声好
and I have someone you want. Go ahead, say hello.
开车离开 无论你在哪
Drive away. Wherever you are,
直接走…
just drive away...
爸爸… 让他接电话
Dad... Put him back on the phone.
他现在在休息
Well, he's resting now
而且说实话 我觉得 他给你的这个建议很不好
and frankly, I think he's giving you bad advice.
要是他出任何事…
Anything happens to him...
你怎么？要杀了我？得了吧弗兰克 我了解你
You'll what? Kill me? Come on, Frank. I know you.
你是个好士兵
You were a good soldier.
你要做好士兵该做的
And you'll do what a good soldier always does.
你得服从命令 所以仔细听好了
You'll follow the orders. So listen to me very closely.
如果你想再见到你爸爸
If you ever wish to see your father alive again,
就完全按照我说的做
you'll do exactly what I say.
狗日的
Son of a bitch!
- 大型的黑色SUV - 驾驶员呢
- A big, black SUV. - Occupants?
就不能别插手？
Couldn't stay away?
有新交易
There's a new deal.
我还以为你说你从不…
I thought you said you never...
那是在他抓走我爸爸之前
That was before he took my dad.
听着 我之所以掺和进来 就是为了你和我爸爸
Listen, I'm in this shit because of you and so is my dad.
所以不管你同不同意 我们都要去见卡拉索夫
So whether you agree or not we're going to see Karasov
现在马上带着账本到他的游艇上去
on his yacht right now with the ledger.
我之前帮了你一个忙 我现在要你帮我一次
I was all for you, now I need you to do one for me.
我们有的选择吗？
Do we have a choice?
没有
Not really.
我们会帮你
We'll help you.
不要再耍花招 不要再说废话
No more games. No more bullshit.
吉娜在哪？
Where's Gina?
她走了 回家人身边了
She left. Back to her family.
别骗我
Don't lie to me.
卡拉索夫以为我们只有3个人
Karasov assumes that there is only three of us
而那就是他要找的 你不觉的吗
and that's what he is looking for. Don't you think?
所以我们总是把一个人分开
This is why we always kept someone separate.
这样我们谁都走不了 那就是我们的交易
So one of us could get away. That was our deal.
去把你爸爸救回来
Let's get your father back.
欢迎回来 女孩们
Welcome back, girls.
好久不见
Been a long time.
还不够久
Not long enough.
还在为之前的事生气？
Still upset about what happened?
对 有一点
A little bit, yeah.
我还以为你这种约翰·韦恩一样的人 会把一切都放下呢
I thought you John Wayne types just let it roll off your back.
那是过去了
That was the old days.
现在我们会怀恨在心 而且必定复仇
Now we hold grudges and get revenge.
为了什么复仇？
Revenge for what?
你那辆车专门改装过
That car of yours is a real step up
就是用来武装押运的
from driving a military convoy truck.
你这是自找的 弗兰克
You know, you brought this on yourself, Frank.
你排里的每个人都不干净 他们可是赚了很多钱
Everyone in your platoon played ball, they made a lot of money.
如果你带着剩下的钱
It would have been easier
直接离开事情会简单得多
if you just went along with the rest, you know.
我不是去赚钱 我是去打仗的
I wasn't there to make money. I was there to fight a war.
我不会跟你这样的人做生意
I don't play ball with people like you.
我可没法评价你的国家
Well, I can't speak to the arrangements
如何使用军事手段达成目的
your country's military makes to get jobs done.
我只是很庆幸从中获益的也有我
I'm just happy I was on the side that profited from it.
我只希望你遭到报应
Well, let's just hope you get what's coming to you.
乔 安娜 玛利亚 很高兴你们能加入我们
Qiao, Anna, Maria, glad you could join us.
我爸爸在哪？
Where's my dad?
你们谁把账本带来了吗
Did one of you bring the ledger?
现在 我爸爸在哪
Now where's my dad?
- 我说… - 我听到了
- I said... - I heard you.
[俄语]
你应该有计划吧 儿子
I assume you have a plan, Junior.
这怎么回事？
What is this?
我们还想问你
You tell us.
这什么意思
What's that supposed to mean?
你召集开会
You called the meeting.
我什么都没召集
I didn't call anything.
别废话了 你这儿什么情况
Cut this shit. What's this about?
首先 我找到了从你手里偷东西的人
Well, for one, I found the people who stole from you.
好吧 他就站在那
Right. And he's right there.
听着 我已经受够了 你们在那指控我
Listen, I'm getting pretty sick of you both accusing me
做了我没有做的事
of something I didn't do.
实际上 我把这些人带到这来 是为了杀死他们
As a matter of fact, I brought these people here to kill them.
他撒谎
He's lying.
你他妈谁啊
Who the hell are you?
我是安娜 为他工作的
I'm Anna and I work for him.
他让我抢劫你 于是我去了
He told me to rob you and I did.
我们叫你来是因为你的钱在他那儿
We called you here because he has your money.
让她说
Let her talk.
不然我们不可能回来这里
There's no way we're taking the fall for this.
因为是他抢劫了你们 不是我们
'Cause he robbed you. Not us.
满嘴胡言
You lying bitch.
让他给你看 让他把银行账户给你看
Have him show you. Ask him to show you the bank account.
我才不会给任何人看任何东西
I'm not showing anybody shit.
都是老朋友了
We've been friends for a long time.
也许你应该让我看
Maybe you should.
你会看到每一分钱都在他…
You'll see he has every penny.
闭嘴
Shut up!
这不是你计划的一部分吧？
It's not part of your plan, this, is it, Junior?
我今天早上检查过账户 我只有1亿2000万
I checked the account this morning. I have just over 120 million.
我会放下枪 把那边的平板拿过来
I'm gonna lower my gun. Grab that tablet right there.
我把账户给你 你自己看
Show you the account. You're gonna see for yourself.
这是个好的开始
That's a fair start.
对 宝贝 来吧
Come on, baby. Come on.
好
Yeah!
Okay.
好
Yes!
多谢你的密码 混蛋
Thanks for the code, asshole!
(开始转账)
好了
Okay!
1亿2000万 就像我说的
$120 million. Just as I said.
(余额：3.2亿美元)
给我
Give it to me.
这不可能
This doesn't make sense.
谁说没钱的？
Don't have the money, huh?
你做了什么？
What the hell did you do?
完全按照你的吩咐
Exactly what you told me.
我要撕碎你
I'm gonna rip you up.
不
No!
玛利亚
Maria!
该死
Shit!
快点
Come on.
和你的钱说再见吧
Say goodbye to your money.
(开始转账)
你能把小船放下发动起来吗
You think you can untie the boat and get it started?
我尽量
I'll try!
(其他用户登陆)
什么？
What?
你的计划是什么 儿子
What's the plan, Junior?
我挡住他们
I'll hold them off.
我们2分钟后在小船上碰头
We meet back on the boat in two minutes!
- 能给我4分钟吗 - 好吧
- Can you give me four? - Okay.
火力掩护
Cover fire!
这不是开玩笑吗 你怎么枪都不带
Oh, you got to be kidding. Why do you never carry a gun?
你就不能别找事了吗
You ever think about being less critical?
快点 我们走
Come on, come on, let's go!
好 听我倒数 3 2 1 走 走 走
Okay. On my count! Three, two, one! Go! Go! Go!
好了
Okay.
该死
Shit.
(拒绝访问)
混蛋
You jerk!
该死
Dammit!
吉娜 不 不 不 不
Gina! No, no, no, no, no.
坚持住
Stay with me!
没事了 没事了
It's okay. It's okay.
(转账完成)
坚持住 坚持住 坚持住
Stay with me, stay with me. Stay with me, stay with me.
对不起 弗兰克
I'm sorry, Frank.
不 不 不
No, no, no.
- 对不起 - 别死
- I'm sorry. - Stay with me.
再快点 过来
Faster! Go here!
- 上快艇 - 是
- Get on the jet ski! - Yes, sir.
抓稳了
Hold on!
快点
Come on!
别动
Don't move!
弗兰克
Frank!
不
No!
你应该在有机会的时候加入我的
You should have joined me when you had the chance, Frank.
别动
Don't move!
这一切都是你设计的
You set this up.
你把见面安排在游艇上
You called the meeting on the yacht
并确保我父亲被绑架了
and made sure my dad was kidnapped,
那样一来 我就会帮你把剩下的事情做完
so I'd be here to help you finish the job.
呆着别动
Stay where you are!
现在你要杀了我 因为我是最后的牺牲品
And now you're going to shoot me because I'm a loose end.
剩下的唯一一个 知道你罪行的人
The last person left to name you for your crimes.
我在找到办法之前无法停手
I can't stop until I get all the way out.
问题是 如果你要杀了我
The question is, if you were supposed to kill me then,
那你之前为何救我？
why did you save my life?
别说了
Stop.
求你别说了
Please stop.
你的朋友们因你而死 安娜
Your friends died for you, Anna.
我也愿意为她们而死
Like I would have died for them.
我只希望你这么做是值得的
I just hope whatever you got out of it was worth it.
我很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
你得走了
You'd better go.
就这样？
That's the deal?
就这样
That's the deal.
我再告诉你 但这不会有什么不同
I'll tell you again, but it won't be any different.
我为依云水工作 我是销售员
I work for Evian. I was delivering water.
我到了那里 发现那里到处是尸体
I get there, there are dead bodies everywhere.
然后两个家伙乘着快艇和摩托艇出现了
Then two guys roar off on a speedboat and a jet ski.
这个人呢？
This one?
在船上
On the boat, yeah.
- 摩托艇呢？- 我不知道
- And the jet ski? - I don't know!
不管他是谁 他都是嫌疑人
Because whoever he was, he will be tried for murder.
听着 我不能告诉你我不知道的事情 我没见过那家伙
Look, I can't tell you what I don't know. I didn't see the guy.
说得真好
How convenient.
我想我们结束了 对吗？
I guess we're done here, right?
如果没有 那就给我个什么罪名
'Cause if not, then please charge me with something,
否则你就是在浪费我们的时间
otherwise you're wasting both our times.
你可以走了
You can go.
谢谢你 警官
Thank you, Inspector.
你真好
Very good of you.
再见
Goodbye.
(犯罪皇帝被杀)
在警察局待了12小时
Twelve hours in a police station.
你知道那对我来说有多丢脸吗？
Do you know how humiliating that is for me?
为何你不告诉我你想回去 好好喝一杯呢？
Why don't you tell me all about it over a good bottle of wine?
你总算说了句聪明话
Finally you say something smart.
∮ 也许我们应该 也许我们应该敲响天堂之门 ∮
∮ Maybe we should, maybe we should knock on heaven's door. ∮
∮ 我们没必要去酒店 ∮
∮ We don't need to go to the liquor store. ∮
∮ 你让我嗨起来    嗨起来 ∮
∮ You give me that high.    Get me high. ∮
∮ 比金子还好    比金子还好 ∮
∮ It's better than gold.    It's better than gold. ∮
∮ 你很努力    你很努力 ∮
∮ You're making it hard.    You're making it hard. ∮
∮ 让我很谨慎    让我很谨慎 ∮
∮ For me to go slow.    For me to go slow. ∮
∮ 你让我嗨起来 ∮
∮ You give me that high. ∮
∮ 比金子还好 ∮
∮ It's better than gold. ∮
∮ 你让事情变得棘手 ∮
∮ You're making it hard. ∮
∮ 拜托 别这么无情 ∮
∮ Please, don't you act so ruthlessly. ∮
∮ 我们都是狂热的动物 ∮
∮ Oh, we're fanatical Rabid animals. ∮
∮ 拜托 没人需要你的看法 ∮
∮ Please, no one needs your point of view. ∮
∮ 不 我们是激烈的动物 ∮
∮ No, we're fanatical Rabid animals. ∮
∮ 拜托 别这么无情 ∮
∮ Please, don't you act so ruthlessly. ∮
∮ 我们是激烈的动物 ∮
∮ Oh, we are cannibals Rabid animals. ∮
∮ 拜托 没人需要你的看法 ∮
∮ Please, no one needs your point of view. ∮
∮ 热情的动物 ∮
∮ Oh, rabid animals Rabid animals. ∮
∮ Rabid animals. ∮
∮ 上帝 生活是美好的 ∮
∮ Oh, good Lord, life is bitter and sweet. ∮
∮ 有时好 有时坏 ∮
∮ Sometimes on my knees Sometimes on my feet. ∮
∮ 你让我嗨起来    嗨起来 ∮
∮ You give me that high.    Get me high. ∮
∮ 比金子还好    比金子还好 ∮
∮ It's better than gold.    It's better than gold. ∮
∮ 你让事情棘手 ∮
∮ You're making it hard. ∮
妈妈
Mama!
∮ 让我谨慎    让我谨慎 ∮
∮ For me to go slow.    For me to go slow. ∮
∮ 你让我嗨 ∮
∮ You give me that high. ∮
∮ 比金子还好 ∮
∮ It's better than gold. ∮
∮ 你让事情棘手 ∮
∮ You're making it hard. ∮
∮ 拜托 别那么无情 ∮
∮ Please, don't you act so ruthlessly. ∮
∮ 我们是热情的动物 ∮
∮ We're fanatical Rabid animals. ∮
∮ 拜托 没人需要你的观点 ∮
∮ Please, no one needs your point of view. ∮
∮ 不 我们是热情的动物 ∮
∮ No, we're fanaticals Rabid animals. ∮
∮ 拜托 别这么无情 ∮
∮ Please, don't you act so ruthlessly. ∮
∮ 我们是热情的动物 ∮
∮ Oh, we are cannibals Rabid animals. ∮
∮ 拜托 没人需要你的观点 ∮
∮ Please, no one needs your point of view. ∮
∮ 热情的动物 热情的动物 ∮
∮ Oh, rabid animals Rabid animals. ∮
∮ 热情的动物 ∮
∮ Rabid animals. ∮
如果你见到她们 不要犹豫
If you ever meet them, don't hesitate.
∮ 你的枕套上有口红印 ∮
∮ Red lipstick on your pillowcase. ∮
∮ 你大受欢迎 ∮
∮ Look at you You've been down for the chase. ∮
∮ 疾如风 利如刃 ∮
∮ Quick as a whip And sharp as a knife. ∮
∮ 让你驾驭生活 ∮
∮ Make you a promise The ride of your life. ∮
∮ 没必要讲道理 ∮
∮ Doesn't have to make sense. ∮
∮ 我宁愿还击 ∮
∮ And I'd rather fight back again. ∮
∮ 独自一人 难道你不知道 ∮
∮ All alone Baby, don't you see. ∮
∮ 如果我们无法彼此拥有 ∮
∮ If I can't have you You can't have me. ∮
∮ 我只有幻想 ∮
∮ On my own within my fantasies. ∮
∮ 如果我们无法彼此拥有 ∮
∮ If I can't have you You can't have me. ∮
∮ 天鹅绒窗帘和壁炉 ∮
∮ Velvet curtains and a fireplace. ∮
∮ 皮草和玫瑰 ∮
∮ Leather couches and rose bouquets. ∮
∮ 我已经麻木不仁 ∮
∮ Torn by my senses I'm paralyzed. ∮
∮ 我已经慢慢淡忘 ∮
∮ I've gone too far to realize. ∮
∮ 没必要讲道理 ∮
∮ Doesn't have to make sense. ∮
∮ 我宁愿还击 ∮
∮ And I'd rather fight back again. ∮
∮ 独自一人 你懂吗 ∮
∮ All alone Baby, don't you see. ∮
∮ 我们无法彼此拥有 ∮
∮ If I can't have you You can't have me. ∮
∮ 我只有幻想 ∮
∮ On my own Within my fantasies. ∮
∮ 我们无法彼此拥有 ∮
∮ If I can't have you You can't have me. ∮
∮ 你无法拥有我 ∮
∮ Oh, you can't have me. ∮
∮ You can't have me. ∮
∮ 噢 噢 ∮
∮ Oh, oh. ∮
∮ Oh, oh.∮
∮ 你无法 你无法 ∮
∮ Oh, you can't, you can't, you can't. ∮
∮ 不 你无法 你无法 你无法 ∮
∮ No, you can't, you can't, you can't. ∮
∮ 不 不 ∮
∮ No, no. ∮
∮ 你无法 你无法 ∮
∮ You can't, you can't, you can't. ∮
∮ 你独自一人 ∮
∮ All alone Baby, don't you see. ∮
∮ 我们无法彼此拥有 ∮
∮ If I can't have you You can't have me. ∮
∮ 我只有幻想 ∮
∮ On my own And in my fantasies. ∮
∮ 我们无法彼此拥有 ∮
∮ If I can't have you You can't have me. ∮
∮ 不 不 ∮
∮ No, no. ∮
∮ 你无法拥有我 ∮
∮ You can't have me. ∮
∮ 你独自一人 ∮
∮ All alone Baby, don't you see. ∮
∮ 我们无法彼此拥有 ∮
∮ If I can't have you You can't have me. ∮
∮ 我只有幻想 ∮
∮ On my own And in my fantasies. ∮
∮ 我们无法彼此拥有 ∮
∮ If I can't have you You can't have me. ∮
∮ 不 不 ∮
∮ No, no. ∮
∮ 你无法拥有我 ∮
∮ You can't have me. ∮